John Elijah Hurn

Full-Stack Software Engineer

(970)457-0869 · hurnelijahboat@gmail.com · Denver, CO · elijahhurn.com · linkedin.com/in/elijahhurn/ · github.com/ElijahHCO

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Certified Full-stack Web Developer with a positive mentality and a background in service and sales. Experienced in a variety of programming languages and frameworks including JavaScript, React.js, and Node.js. Skilled at solving unique business challenges by developing user-friendly applications and maintaining and enhancing existing applications.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Python | Libraries and Frameworks - Node.js, Express.js

Database - MongoDB, Mongoose | Other - RESTful Routing JSON

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

February 2022 - Present

SnowShelves, Denver, CO

Developer

- Prompt: Design an app using technologies covered in the previous week in class. Technologies include React, Node.js, Express.js
- Developed a mobile-friendly web app allowing users to find and sort snowboard and ski equipment.
- Achieved experience in building and debugging complex systems in a solo environment.
- Built the entire app from top to bottom leveraging React, Mongoose, and Express.

Kantata, Denver, CO

Developer

- Prompt: Design an app using technologies learned in the previous week in class in a team environment.
- Constructed a mobile-friendly web app allowing users to buy/sell musical instruments.
- Established experience in building and debugging complex systems in a team environment.
- Provided significant contributions made to database construction, backend service construction, and front-end component design leveraging Javascript, Express, HTML, and CSS.

Portfolio/elijahhurn.com

Developer

- Prompt: Design a portfolio website that can represent yourself and be used as a tool to highlight some skills and projects you have accomplished.
- Utilized HTML, CSS, and Javascript skills learned in the first two weeks of class to build and fill out the portfolio design.
- Created application with a mobile-first approach and styled the application using Styled-Components and CSS with flexbox layouts.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

evo, Rental Shop Associate | Denver, CO

September 2021 - April 2022

- Maintain, manage, and delegate store operational procedures on a day-to-day basis.
- Implement strategies for rental operations to increase efficiency in the peak winter rental season.
- Build equipment that made checking rental inventory smooth and easy for rental associates.

Brauhaus, Bartender | Steamboat Springs, CO

July 2020 - March 2021

- Created drinks and helped design bar operations that made things run smoother for day to day
- Generated sales directly through communication with guests by suggesting drinks/drink specials.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE

Software Engineering Immersive

February 2022 - Present

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.